Frank G. Speck Papers 1903-1950 Mss.Ms.Coll.126
American Philosophical Society
- Subcollection I. Frank G. Speck Papers, 1897-1950; 10 linear feet
  - Series I. Research Material, 1903-1950; 8.25 linear feet
    - II. Circumboreal
      - B. Montagnais-Naskapi
        - 5. Religion
          - Religion -- c. "Game Totems Among the Northeastern Algonkins.", 1916; II(4B5c); 2 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 3)
            F&S 2093
          - Religion -- d. Animism in Algonkian Mentality, II(4B5d); 1 item; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 3)
            F&S 2297
          - Religion -- e. Miscellaneous notes on Montagnais-Naskapi Religion, 1929; II(4B5e); 6 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 3)
            Undated, incomplete letter of John M. Cooper to ? concerning scapulimancy. Field notes concerning scapulimRncy, bear ceremony, drumming, etc. 1 sheet of Naskapi names of moons (religious). Letter of George Heye, to Speck, Jan. 3, 1926, concerning a missionary book in Montagnais. Images note: Pencil and ink sketches of scapulimancy, bear ceremony, drumming. F&S 2308
        - 6. Linguistic
          - Linguistic -- a. Miscellaneous linguistic materials, n.d.; II(4B6a); 3 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 3)
            Charts display equivalents in 7 dialects for 30 nouns, adverbs, pronouns, and verb "to see"
            F&S 2326
          - Linguistic -- b. Montagnais loan words from English, n.d.; II(4B6b); 6 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 3)
            Vocabulary lists with Montagnais and Mistassini equivalents. Also miscellaneous notes, 3p.
            F&S 2328
          - Linguistic -- c. Montagnais and Mistssinni Texts, 1915; II(4B6c); 8 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 3)
            Montagnais texts with interlinear translation; 2 maps of hunting territory and notes; Tadoussac texts with interlinear translation; several English texts; list of kinship terms; Escoumains text with interlinear translation. Mistassini texts with interlinear translations. English texts from Mistassini and Lake St. John hands. Notebook relating to Naskapi religion; also 10p. of Michikaman Band texts. Images note: Pencil sketches, maps.
            F&S 2329
        - 7. Moisie Band
          - Moisie Band -- A Field notes, 1930, Moisie and St. Marguerite Bands, II(4B7); 1 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 3)
            Names of informants for various bands; Seven Islands data on sorcery; miscellaneous material.
            F&S 2303
        - 8. Ste. Augustine Band
          - Ste. Augustine Band -- a. Field notes, 1935, Ste. Augustine Band, 1935 - 1936; II(4B8); 12 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 3)
            Account books list expenses and press botanical and entomological specimens. Notebook includes miscellaneous ethnographic data as well as designs. Map of St. Augustin village. 1p. sketch of animals with Naskapi names; 2 hand-drawn maps of St. Augustin region; miscellaneous materials and family histories. Letters: W. B. Cabot to Speck, July 29, 1930, A.L.S., 1p., concerning his (Cabot's) visit to Labrador; Hayward Hayne to Speck, Sept. 7, 1935, and Mar. 1, 1936, A.L.S., 4p. and 10p., concerning winter activities and Hudson's Bay Company post at St. Augustin; A. Poucher, missionary, to Speck, May 18, 1936, A.L.S., 1p. Images note: 26 pencil and ink sketches maps, village, animals. F&S 2304
        - 9. Mistassini Band
          - Mistassini Band -- a. Miscellaneous notes, Mistassini, 1915-1930; II(4B9a); 8 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 3)
            Concerns hunting territories of Mistassini, Waswanipi, Tête de Boule, Chicoutimi. Ethnographic data on childbirth and chiefs.
            F&S 2311
          - Mistassini Band -- b. Document, refering to Pointe Speck, 1946-1948; II(4B9b); 3 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 3)
            Images note: Includes 1p. blueprint of Lake Mistassini, P.Q., showing Pointe Speck. Letter of Jacques Rousseau (Director of Montreal Botanical Garden) to Speck, Nov. 3, 1948, 1p. A.L.S., concerning the adoption of the name Pointe Speck.
            F&S 2300
          - Mistassini Band -- c. Field Notes, 1911-1930, II(4B9c); 29 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 3)
            6 English folkloristic texts, 1919, 1921, and 1930. A notebook of Montagnais and Mistassini texts in English, 1917; a 17p. typed version of Mistassini tales (1925) taken from above. A brief introductory statement, "Montagnais myths and tales from the Lower St. Lawrence"; ethnohistoric material; miscellaneous notes; 4p. concerning Gay Head Indians. Letter of Edward Sapir to Speck, June 18, 1912, 1p. A.L.S., concerning Cree-Montagnais linguistic relationship and obtaining of museum specimens. Unrelated: Some notes by Gladys Tantaquidgeon on Gay Head Wampanoag.
            F&S 2310
        - 10. Lake St. John Band
          - Lake St. John Band -- a. "Family Hunting Territories of the Lake St. John Montaganais and Neighboring Bands.", II(4B10a); 5 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 3)
            Typed M.S. with additions.
            F&S 2302
          - Lake St. John Band -- b. Field notes, II(4B10b); 7 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 3)
            16p. on native names of specimens and artifacts, both Lake St. John and Mistassini: 4p. give account of Wabeno and names of specimens.
            F&S 2305
        - 11. Davis Inlet Naskapi
          - Davis Inlet Naskapi -- a. Waugh's notes, 1923-1924; II(4B11); 5 items; Waugh, F. W., (Frederick Wilkerson), 1872-1924 (Box 3)
            13p. of notes, mostly in hand of Frank G. Speck, obtained from F. W. Waugh. Letters of Waugh to Speck, Dec. 18, 1923, and Jan. 19, 1924, 1p. and 1p. T.L.S., concerning Davis Inlet group; copy of William Duncan Strong to Speck, Sept. 4, 1930, concerning Davis Inlet band.
            F&S 2322
        - 12. Tadoussac-Escoumains Band
          - Tadoussac-Escoumains Band -- a. Field notes, II(4B12); 7 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 3)
            Ethnobotanical data; plant names and medical uses; miscellaneous materials including names of museum specimens and myths.
            F&S 2320
        - 13. 7 Islands Band
          - 7 Islands Band -- a. Miscellaneous field notes, 1924-1925; II(4B13); 11 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 3)
            Several texts with interlinear translations; house data; names of animals. 1p. friendly letter, in French, of Marie Louise Ambroise, Aug. 22, 1924, to Speck.
            F&S 391
      - C. Algonquin
        - to Frank Speck, 1924; II(2C1); 1 item; Sapir, Edward, 1884-1939 (Box 1)
          "Linguistic analogues to Wiyot-Yorok" Discusses his postulated Wiyot-Yurok-Algonquian relationship; mentions his work on Subtiaba. Outlines relationships in and around Hokan-Coahuiltecan. Some discussion of migrations, seeing Athabaskan as late arrival.
          F&S 2061
        - Algonquin field notes, n.d.; II(2C2); 4 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 1)
          One notebook contains linguistic notes, informant and population data for Waswanipi, Abitibi, Temiskaming, Nipissing, Algonquian. The other, dated June 1, contains Temiskaming ethnography, and (in English), Wisilèdjak (Wiskyjack) text. Temagami ethnology and texts (in English) and 1 Iroquois legend. Use Film 1429 Reel 1.
          F&S 369
      - D. Beothuk
        - to Frank Speck, 1922; II(2D1); 1 item; Moorehead, Warren King, 1866-1939 (Box 1)
          Discusses his New England archaeological field work. Doubts Red Paint People of Maine were Beothuks; difference of art. Labels for University Museum artifacts from collections of Moorehead.
          F&S 462
        - Miscellaneous notes on Beothuk, 1911 - 1922; II(2D2); 4 items (Box 1)
          Boas, Franz. Letter to Frank G. Speck, December 17, 1911 -- Discusses Boethuk report. Dahl, Richard S. Letter to Frank G. Speck, December 30, 1911 - In his career as mining engineer in Newfoundland he has opened many Beothuk sites; offers aid. Howley, James P. Letters to Frank G. Speck, December 12, 1911 and May 18, 1912 -- Howley writes Speck of the latter's meeting a Beothuk survivor; doubts authenticity, but would like to know more. Images note: Folder includes newsclipping of Oct. 15, 1911, on Speck's discovery and a portion of Howley's book printing a Beothuk vocabulary with Speck pencil notes:184-186. Messurier, William L. Letter to Dr. Bowman, February 15, 1922 -- Encloses article on Newfoundland extracted from "The Great Historical, Genealogical, and Poetical Dictionary... " (London, 1701).
          F&S 457, 459, 460, 461
      - E. Athapascan
        - Miscellaneous Notes, n.d.; II(2E1); 10 items (Box 1)
          Reading notes.
          F&S 429
      - F. Ojibwa
        - Review of Coleman on Ojibway Designs, n.d.; II(2F1); 1 item; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 2)
          of Sister Bernard Coleman: Decorative designs of the Ojibwa of northern Minnesota [1949].
          F&S 2519
        - Miscellaneous notes, 1927 - 1948; II(2F2); 4 items (Box 2)
          Woodman, Henry. Letter to Frank G. Speck, July 16, 1948 -- Discusses decline of crafts among Bear Island Indians (Temagami). Speck, Frank G. Letter to Chief Mitchele Buckshot; Maniwaki, Québec, February 10, 1927 -- Requests buckskin and beadwork. Images note: Newspaper clippings, pencil sketches, maps, and photomechanical prints of utensils, dwelling, portraits.
          F&S 2516, 2523
        - to Frank G. Speck, 1931; II(2F3); 4 items; Hallowell, A. Irving, (Alfred Irving), 1892-1974 (Box 2)
          Describes incidents on field trip to Berens River Saulteaux, Sweet Grass Cree (mentions attitude of Cree to Leonard Bloomfield) and Cold Lake Chipewyan; festivals, etc. Letter of Speck to Hallowell, Aug. 3, 1931, with pencilled responses of Hallowell to questions asked.
          F&S 2501
        - Matagama Ojibwa notes, 1914-1938; II(2F4); 21 items (Box 2)
          Includes 2p. phonetic key; 1p. letter (carbon) of Frank G. Speck to Samuel (i.e., James) Miller of Gogama, Feb. 18, 1928, requesting ethnographic and map data; 2 maps, 1 of Mattagama hunting territories, boundaries in ink; 1p. typed reading notes (and a carbon); Feb. 1928 "Romance Story," 15p. sketch of a play for Mattagama Otcipwè. Burgeese, J. A. Letters to Frank G. Speck (Jan. 13 and Feb. 24, 1938). Burgesse sends drawing of "flesher" used by Oiibwa; encloses list of hunting territories and biographical information on owners. Learmouth, D. H. Letters to Frank G. Speck (Feb. 22 and 29, and Oct. 2, 1928). Learmouth, a factor for Hudson's Bay Co. at Waswanippi, recounts his experiences in adjudicating Matagama land inheritance; provides ethnographic data sought by Speck from Samuel (i.e., James) Miller of Gogama; and gives data on hunting territories.
          F&S 2498, 2508, 2517
        - Ojibwa Hunting territories, n.d.; II(2F5); 3 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 2)
          Brief popular account, refuting Roosevelt (1889-1896), who had denied that Indians have a sense of property. 1p. typed notes from Copway (1847), and 1p. notes.
          F&S 2518
        - Tamagami myths, n.d.; II(2F6); 5 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 2)
          5 English texts.
          F&S 2520
      - G. Cree
        - Cree syllabary, n.d.; II(2G1); 6 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 2)
          Naskapi names in Cree syllabary; the Lord's Prayer in Cree; miscellaneous syllabary Cree words. Images note: 79 pictographs
          F&S 788
      - H. Miscellaneous
        - Tete de Boule, n.d.; II(2H1); 1 item; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 2)
          Miscellaneous notes on informants; word list. Notes on reverse of 2p. letter of W. C. Orchard (Heye Foundation) to Speck, Dec. 10, 1931.
          F&S 2330
    - III. Northeast (ill-defined area west of Mississippi, north of corn-growing limit, south to approximately Mason-Dixon Line)
      - A. General
        - "Remnants of the Eastern Indian Tribes", III(5A1); 1 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 3)
          Brief discussion of location of New England Algonkians.
          F&S 336
        - "The Persistence of the Mound Builder's Culture Among Recent Indian Tribes", 1916; III(5A2); 1 item; Linton, Ralph, 1893-1953 (Box 3)
          Master's thesis, University of Pennsylvania. Attempts through historical accounts to show persistence both of building of mounds and of artifacts, thought to be prehistoric, and argues that white contact produced the cultural loss.
          F&S 1217
        - Wampum - miscellaneous notes, 1913-1920; III(5A3); 8 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 3)
          Includes letters of L. P. O. Picard to Speck, April 24, and May 12, 1914, concerning a belt in Picard's possession; I. B. Delay to Speck, Aug. 23, 1913, and Jan. 1914, concerning beads and sale of belts; Sankey Swan to Speck, Mar. 15, 1914; Josiah Hill of Ohsweken to Speck, June 11, 1914, offering to send wampum string and describing Nanticoke belt; Waiter Channing Wyman, collector, to Speck, Dec. 18, 1920, discussing Shenandoah belt and a Penobscot belt in his possession; W. C. Orchard, Heye Foundation, to Speck, concerning bibliography on wampum.
          F&S 2321
        - Observations on the Northeast in general, 1941; III(5A4); 9 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 3)
          Notes used by Speck in summing up the symposium, Man in Northeastern America, meeting of the American Anthropological Association, 1941, at Phillips Academy, Andover. Brief comments on the various papers. On verse of 4p. are letters: Frederick Johnson to Speck, Oct. 13, 1941, Typed L.S., 2p., concerning meeting plans; and James B. Griffin to Johnson, 1941, Typed L., 2p., copy, concerning his paper. Also, 3 copies of printed program and one typed Tentative Program.
          F&S 1256
        - "The Agricultural Tribes of the Northeast", 1941; III(5A5); 1 item; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005 (Box 3)
          Principally a discussion of Iroquois and Algonkian maize culture. Attempts to date usage. Notes of Speck on the 1941 Man in Northeastern America conference on reverse of typed sheets.
          F&S 1639
        - "The Place of the Dorset Eskimo in the Northeast", n.d.; III(5A6); 1 item; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004 (Box 3)
          F&S 1313
        - "Linguistic Considerations of Northeastern America", n.d.; III(5A7); 2 items; Voegelin, C. F., and Erminie Wheeler-Voegelin (Box 3)
          Special emphasis on midwestern tribes, particularly Sauk and Fox. 1p. note of Frank G. Speck, criticizing the paper.
          F&S 1295
        - "Circumboreal Archaeology", n.d.; III(5A8); 1 item; Spaulding, A. C. (Box 3)
          A brief statement of a lengthier paper.
          F. S. 1232
        - "A Cultural Perspective of Northeastern Area Archaeology", n.d.; III(5A9); 1 item; McKern, W. C., (Will Carleton), 1892- (Box 3)
          F&S 1218
        - "Physical Types of the Northeast", n.d.; III(5A10); 1 item; Howells, W. W., (William White), 1908-2005 (Box 3)
          Brief statement of formal paper.
          F&S 1304
        - "Archeological Manifestations in the Northeast", n.d.; III(5A11); 1 item; Ritchie, W. A. (Box 3)
          F&S 1224
        - "The Culture of the Northeastern Hunter", 1941; III(5A12); 2 items; Cooper, John M., (John Montgomery), 1881-1949 (Box 3)
          A draft with very little similarity to tile published version. Contains generalizations about shared culture traits in the area. 1p. note of Cooper to Frank G. Speck, Sept. 9, 1941.
          F&S 1246
        - to Frank G. Speck, 1918-1919; III(5A13); 2 items; Sapir, Edward, 1884-1939 (Box 3)
          Concerning Speck (1918a); Sapir sees Yurok comparisons; discusses general linguistic relationships; excited about reduction of language stocks; inquires after possible typographical errors, pp. 157-158 of article.
          F&S 362 and 2062
      - B. Iroquois
        - 1. General Iroquois
          - General Iroquois (6 Nations) -- a. "The Long-House Man", n.d.; III(6B1a); 1 item; Moses, Jesse, Jr. (Box 4)
            Discusses relationship (from point of view of a Christian Indian) of Christianity and long-house religion; emphasizes government Indian policy; expects victory of Christianity.
            F&S 1647
          - General Iroquois (6 Nations) -- b. "Canadian Christian Indians Revert to Pagan Beliefs", 1929-1930; III(6B1b); 1 item; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 4)
            Argues that better-educated Indians have "gone native" as a means of escaping bureaucracy and clerical greed.
            F&S 1659
          - General Iroquois (6 Nations) -- c. Iroquois burial customs, 1888; III(6B1c); 1 item; Buck, Chief John (Box 4)
            Letter to George S. Conover Re Iroquois burial customs.
            F&S 1637
          - General Iroquois (6 Nations) -- d. Wabanaki War with Iroquois, n.d.; III(6B1d); 7 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 4)
            Miscellaneous notes Iroquois, wampum.
            F&S 1789
          - General Iroquois (6 Nations) -- e. Seizure of Iroquois wampum by Canadian government, 1914 - 1926; III(6B1e); 6 items (Box 4)
            Letters: Josiah Hill, Ohsweken, to Frank G. Speck, April 27, 1914, concerning photos of wampum, exchange of wampum with Seth Newhouse; same to same, n.d., complaining that British are unmindful of Loyalist Iroquois aid during eighteenth century; Frank G. Speck to Chief David S. Hill, c.c., Jan. l(i, 1925, concerning dispute with Canadian Indian department (seizure of wampum: loose beads and strings); David S. Hill to Speck, Feb. 15, 1925, stating MS. of Six Nations constitution has reappeared and will be compared with Scott copy (Scott, 1912); Speck to Dr. A. Leon Hatzon, Nov. 3, 1925 and April 17, 1926, criticizing book on wampum by Hatzon; A. Leon Hatzon to Speck, April 15, 1926, reply.
            F&S 1655
          - General Iroquois (6 Nations) -- f. Letters to Frank Speck offering to sell code, etc., 1915-1916; III(6B1f); 2 items; Newhouse, Seth (Box 4)
            1915 Asks, at suggestion of F. W. Waugh, that Speck secure shell for wampum for Newhouse. 1916: Offers to sell Speck his history manuscript, which he has been working on since 1885 [No. 1650]; will try to secure some wampum.
            F&S 1648, 1649
          - General Iroquois (6 Nations) -- g. Nanticokes visit 6 Nations with Frank G. Speck, n.d.; III(6B1g); 1 item (Box 4)
            A document describing meeting of Delaware, Nanticoke, and Canadian Iroquois in presence of Speck; recounts injustices suffered by Indians in United States and Canada.
            F&S 1755, also 2358
          - General Iroquois (6 Nations) -- h. Cayuga Indian claim, 1914-1926; III(6B1h); 2 items (Box 4)
            Letter of David Jamieson (Des-ka-heh) to Speck, April 4, 1914, concerning making secure Indian rights to land at Ohsweken. Copy of letter of Fred K. Nielsen to George P. Decker, Mar. 27, 1926, with MS. note of Decker to Speck concerning validity of Cayuga land claims before American-British Arbitral Tribunal.
            F&S 552
          - General Iroquois (6 Nations) -- i. Cayuga Indian representative in Onandaga Council, 1925; III(6B1i); 1 items; Menzie, Decker V. (Box 4)
            Concerning Speck's aid on Deskaheh's speech. Newsclipping included.
            F&S 558
          - General Iroquois (6 Nations) -- j. Letter to Chief Gibson, 1914; III(6B1j); 1 item; Ioma, John (Box 4)
            Letter introduces Frank G. Speck to Gibson, with request that he be given data and wampum.
            F&S 1643
          - General Iroquois (6 Nations) -- k. Miscellaneous notes, 1936-1948; III(6B1k); 24 items (Box 4)
            Letters and notes concerning Speck (1945), and masks. Includes: 2p. sketches of masks; 36 slips of miscellaneous Iroquois references, notes, and Wyandot data; 1p. quotation concerning Delaware as women theme; bibliographical note (to Robert T. Hatt, Director of Cranbrook Institute of Science); note on Iroquois art. Letters to Speck include: John L. Buck, Burlington, Ontario, May 18, 1936, offering to sell masks; Merle H. Deardorff, Nov. 29, 1945, concerning Speck and Fenton field work and Speck (1945); Robert T. Hatt, Nov. 18, 1943, concerning publication of Speck (1945); John E. Jacobs, Jan. 12, 1948, concerning Iroquois songs, seeking feathers, sale of bow and arrows; W. N. Fenton, Nov. 15, 1948, concerning wampum strings; Arthur C. Parker, Sept. 11, 1947, concerning splint work of Seneca, basketry-mentions Stockbridge, Mahican, and Brotherton; Mrs. Alfred Martin, May 27 and Feb. 28, 1947, conceming museum specimens and deer tails; Loren C. Eiseley, July 8, 1940, concerning beaver and Algonkin hunting territory; W. N. Fenton, Sept. 1, 1944, concerning Seneca use of Joe Pye plant. Images note: 9 pencil sketches of Seneca false faces.
            F&S 1662
          - General Iroquois (6 Nations) -- l. [no entry], III(6B1l) (Box 4)
          - General Iroquois (6 Nations) -- m. "Status of the Six Nations." Brief by St. Regis Mohawks, n.d.; III(6B1m); 1 item (Box 4)
            Brief concerning Indian rights against New York and federal government after 1924; also, letter of Muzzy Cook, Julius Cook, and Ray Fadden (Akwesasne Counselor Organization).
            F&S 2262
          - General Iroquois (6 Nations) -- n. Review of Listen for a Lonesome Drum by Carl Cramer, n.d.; III(6B1n); 1 item; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 4)
            A romantic review of a literary work.
            F&S 2267
          - General Iroquois (6 Nations) -- o. Masks (miscellaneous notes), 1934-1944; III(6B1o); 42 items (Box 4)
            Includes: 4 letters of John L. Buck Ohsweken, to Speck, Oct. 23, 1936, to March 5, 1944, concerning masks sent to Speck asking Speck to burn tobacco for mask as suggested by a dream; and, concerning pictures Buck wants of his relatives; also, notes on Iroquois and Eskimo masks and drama, 1p.; 4p. quotations of printed works on corn-husk masks; 3p. notes on function of masks, east; 2p. on drums, northeast; letter of G. E Fenstermaker to Speck, March 15, 1934, offering to sell Cherokee and Iroquois masks; 3p miscellany. Images note: photographs, postcard, illustrations and sketches of Tuscarora, Onondaga masks.
            F&S 1661
            - Rattlesnake mask, 1934-1944
          - General Iroquois (6 Nations) -- p. Reflections on Iroquois religion, 1939-1941; III(6B1p); 10 items (Box 4)
            Draft of article of Speck protesting missionary competition in reservations and emphasizing Christian character of long-house religion. Submitted originally to Newsletter of Home Missions Board, but rejected for its controversial nature. Published in Crozier Quarterly in 1941. Letters discussing the contents: Alban W. Hoopes, Feb. 12, 1940; Thomas Alfred Trip, Feb. 28, 1940; Mark A. Dawber, March 11, 1940 and Nov. 27, 1940; C. E. Schaeffer, Dec. 3, 1940 (quoting M. H. Deardorff); Charles T. Loran, Oct. 20, 1939; Chief Deskaheh, Nov. 9, 1939; Luther H. Ketels, Nov. 5, 1939; W. N. Fenton, Aug. 5, 1941.
            F&S 1664
          - General Iroquois (6 Nations) -- q. Population statistics 1792, 1944; III(6B1q); 2 items; Deardorff, Merle H., d.1971 (Box 4)
            2 memoranda, March 19, 1944 and March 26, 1944, with comments on and copies of population statistics of 1792, given in I. Chapin papers in the O'Reilly Collection of the New-York Historical Society (the originals are in No. 234).
            F&S 1638
        - 2. Mohawk
          - Mohawk -- a. Letter on St. Regis Mohawk, 1942; III(6B2a); 5 items; Rowell, Mary (Box 4)